Neisser, Hans Phillip; Papers ger069
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Hans Philipp Neisser Papers
1918-1971
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ger069
2 cubic ft.
Neisser was a professor of economics at the New School for Social Research. The collection consists of manuscripts, lecture notes, correspondence, reprints of Neisser's publications, and book reviews written by Neisser.
Biographical Sketch
Born into a distinguished professional family, Hans Neisser achieved a considerable reputation during the German phase of his career--first as economic advisor to the Weimar Government, then as coeditor of one of the leading German business magazines, and after 1927 as Deputy Director of Research in the Institute of world Economics at Kiel University. It was there that he published his first major work, Der Tauschwert des Geldes, one of the very few books written outside of the Anglo-American orbit that Keynes quoted with full approval in his Treatise on Money. From the same period dates his generally acknowledged critique of the fundamentals of the Walrasian system.
Neisser's first academic appointment in this country was as Professor of Monetary Theory in the University of Pennsylvania, followed during the war by a responsible position in the Office of Price Administration. In 1943 he joined the Graduate Faculty of the New School, where lie served in a leadership capacity, including tenure as Chairman of the Department of Economics, until his retirement in 1965.
Neisser's teaching and research covered almost the entire scope of economics. Centering on economic theory, his contributions extended to international economics, the history of economic thought, and many fields of applied economics, where he drew on his wide practical experience. Neisser early acknowledged econometrics as an effective tool of empirical research. In collaboration with Franco Modigliani he published in 1953 National Income and International Trade, to date the most comprehensive econometric investigation of: The world-economic relations during the interwar period. Also pioneering was his essay on "The Pricing of Consumer Durables", which appeared in 1959 in Econometrica. Under Neisser's guidance the New School became the first teaching institution in the metropolitan area to establish a training center for econometric study. His work ranges from studies on the New Economics to essays on Marx; from an examination of general overproduction to a critical analysis of the theory of games.
Scope and Contents
Autobiography, undated; correspondence, 1918-1933; lecture notes, course outlines, and examinations, 1942-1968; and drafts, typescripts, and offprints of articles and reviews, 1919-1971. Neisser was a professor of economics at the New School for Social Research.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into two series. Series 1 is Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc. and Series 2 is Reprints & Book reviews.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by Charlotte Neisser, widow of Hans Phillip Neisser, and Ulric Neisser, son of Hans Phillip Neisser, in 1978.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
World War, 1939-1945 -- Refugees.; Economics -- Study and teaching.; World War, 1914-1918.; Lobbying -- New York (State).; Correspondence.; Economics; New School for Social Research (New York, N.Y.: 1919-1997)
- Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc., Undated; 1
  - 247-G Problems in Mathematical Economics - Hans Neisser, 1948 Fall (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    (exams, notes, course outline).
  - Keyne: [Notes on Keyne, comments, course outline: Keynesian and Past Keynesian Economics, and course notes], Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 2)
  - Comments on the Projections in The United States Balance of Payments in 1968 (Brookings Institution), Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 3)
  - The Law of Markets (say's Law), Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 4)
    [Questions and notes from the following courses: Eco 110, Economic Theory 609-G].
  - Rough drafts and completed paper, Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 5)
    [Rough drafts and completed paper: Keynes' Theory of Aggregate Investment, completed paper: Investments & Interest: A Reconsideration by Hans Neisser, and segments of other papers].
  - Lecture notes on Implications and Limitations of the Keynesian Model, 1954 (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 6)
  - Various completed and segmented papers, notes and comments, Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 7)
    Completed papers include: Competitive Equilibrium: Existence and Approach, Static Theory of Aggregate Investment, by Hans Neisser; segments of: General Economic Equilibrium, A Study of Walras and Marshall; and comments on: Heilbronner, The Making of Economic Society.
  - Newspaper clippings. [Hans Neisser's appointment to the Wharton faculty], Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 9)
  - Correspondence and notes, Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 10)
  - Dr. Neisser's Economic Theory I, Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 11)
  - Introduction to Mathematical Economics, Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 12)
    [course outline, notes, review questions].
  - Imperfect Composition, Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 13)
    [course outline, exams, worksheets & notes. The American Economic Review, December 1942].
  - Vellmans. - M [notes], Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 14)
  - Book I-Theory of Circulation. Chapter I-Fundamental Concepts. Chapter III-The Supply of Money, Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 15)
  - Course outlines, Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 16)
    Course outline for: Economic Theory I & Economic Theory II, Keynesian Post Keynesian Economics, Economic Dynamics, including notes, review questions, exams.
  - Hans Neisser's Multiplier [data on subject area; also Econometrics final exam], Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 17)
  - Philosophy (Smith) [note], Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 18)
  - The World and the Mind, Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 19)
  - [Reprint by H. Neisser - In Memoriam: Gerhard Colm-1897-1968, Economic Theory I ans. to review questions, An Outline of the Modus. Operandi of the U.S.A. Economy. In the Early 1960s, by H. Neisser; various course handout material], Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 20)
  - [Notes, comments on E. Burke's Reflections on the French Revolution; copy of The Time Analysis of Demand by Kenneth G. Matheson, correspondences with Dr. L. Currie by H. Neisser], Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 21)
  - Notes on: Cohen, Cogen, Payne, Okun, Russell, Friedman, Demison, Forrester Meltzer & Brunner, Phelps, Miles, Bryon, Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 22)
  - [Course outline and notes for Problems of Economic Dynamics], Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 23)
  - [Outline statistics material OMI], Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 24)
  - ACN - a) T. P. and B. C.; b) Ace; c) Defect; d) M; Dx Extramaterial, Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 25)
  - Excerpts in Dynamics, Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 26)
  - Explaining the Business Cycle, Undated (Box 1 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 27)
  - [Material in Economic Dynamics, course outline, notes, exams, review questions, etc.], Undated (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 1)
  - [Material on Economic Dynamics, general solution of Linear Multi - Sectoral Models; reprints on the combination of Acceleration Effect & Echo Effect], Undated (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 2)
  - Wahan's (-) Law and Say's Law, Undated; copies (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 3)
  - Material on course: Keynesian and Post-Keynesian Economics and material, Undated (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 4)
    Folder on Economic Dynamics.
  - Lewis - Longfind (-), Undated (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 5)
  - Material on International Economics (loose papers)], Undated (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 6)
  - [Tables and charts - appendix /derivation of problem], Undated (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 7)
  - [Manuscript: A First Approach To The Secular Saving Function, Honours Seminar (1954) - Basic Problems of Location Theory; segment of unidentified work by H. Neisser], Undated (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 8)
  - [Correspondence with Prof. Grosswald - his derivation of an equation; dimensions in Keynesian Equations], Undated (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 9)
  - [The Secular Saving Function 1879-1914 by H. Neisser, appendixes and tables], Undated (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 10)
  - [Partial copy of: Circular Velocity in the U.S.A.], Undated (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 11)
  - Economic Theory - course material; Introduction to Economics course material - review questions and exams, Undated (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 12)
  - [Outline; Brookings Model, De Lunnus(-)], Undated (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 13)
  - [A Centenary of Das Kapital, Vol. I, by H. Neisser; various unidentified notes and comments], Undated (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 14)
  - [Segment of an unidentified paper], Undated (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 15)
  - Graphs, Undated (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 16)
  - [Balance Growth and the "Turnpike Theorem", an unidentified paper; another unidentified paper (the first page is missing on the unidentifiable papers)]., Undated (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 17)
  - The Nature of Intransitivity; two unidentifiable papers; segments/other papers, Undated (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 19)
    Exam book, two books: Christian Albrecht's Universität Keil 1665-1965, Social Research, The Idea of Community.
    (big envelope) correspondences, diplomas, passports, letters home.
  - Correspondences, late 1920s-early 1930s (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 20)
    late 1920s-early [including Lowe correspondences, 1932-1933].
  - Diplomas, passports, etc., Undated (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 21)
  - Hans' letters home from the front, 1918 (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 22)
  - Recollections of Hans Neisser (autobiography), Undated (Box 2 (1-Manuscripts, lecture notes, etc.), Folder 23)
- Reprints & Book reviews, Undated; 2
  - Reprints, Undated; 2.1
    - 1) "Cylical Fluctuations and Economic", by Hans Neisser. Extract from Oxford Economic Papers. New Series - Vol-13 No.2, 1961 June; 2 copies
    - 2) "On Equilibrium Growth of Capital and Labor" by Hans Neisser, 1962; 2 copies
      Reprinted from International Economic Review, Vol. 3, No.1
    - 3) "A Pyrrhic Victory", by Hans Neisser, 1958 December
      Reprinted from The Economic Journal, Vol. LXVIII
    - 4) "The Supply Factor In Professor Hicks' Theory Of The Cycle" by Hans Neisser, 1956 December
      Reprinted from The Economic Journal, Vol. LXVI
    - 5) Notes and Memoranda - Industrial Production and Profits In The United Kingdom and The United States: Some Comments by Hans Neisser, 1956 September; 2 copies
      Reprinted from The Economic Journal. Vol. LXVI
    - 6) Notes and Memoranda - The Supply Factor in the Theory of the Cycle -Some Comments by H. Neisser, 1958 March; 2 copies
      Reprinted from T he Economic Journal. Vol. LXVIII
    - 7) "Depreciation, Replacement and Regular Growth", by Hans Neisser, 1955 March; 2 copies
      Reprinted from The Economic Journal, Vol. LXV
    - 8) "Keynes' Aggregate Supply Function" Further Comments by Hans Neisser, 1961 December; 2 copies
      Reprinted from The Economic Journal. Vol. LXXI
    - 9) Zur Lehre von Den Grenzen. Der Verhalterhaftung. Inaugural Dissertation; zur Grlangung der juristischen Doktorwürde Recats und Staatswissensichaftlichen Fakerltat der Universitat Breslau vorgelegt von Hans Neisser-Referendar. Breslau, 1919
    - 10) "L'Oligopole, les anticipations et la théorie Jeux Neisser" by Hans Neisser.Economie Appliquée - Archives de l'Institut de Science Economique Appliquée, 11 2 1949; 2 copies
    - 11) "The Price Level and The Gold Problem" by Hans Neisser, 1941 February; 2 copies
      Reprinted from American Economie Review. Vol. XXX, No. 5
    - 12) The Pricing of Consumers' Durables, by Hans Neisser, 1959 October
      Reprinted from Econometric, Journal of the Econometric Society, Vol. 27, No.4
    - 13) "Permanent" Technological Unemployment" by Hans Neisser, 1942 March; 2 copies
      Reprinted from American Economic Review. Vol. XXXII, No.1
    - 14) "An International Reserve Bank". Comments on the American and British Plans by Hans Neisser, 1943 September; 2 copies
      Reprinted from Social Research. Vol. 10, No.3
    - 15) "Das Oligopol als Nichtnullsummenspiel" by Hans P. Neisser, Undated; 2 copies
      Reprinted from The Review of Economic Bk 25 L, 1-20, 1957/58.
    - 16) "Economic Imperialism Reconsidered by Hans Neisser, 1960 Spring; 2 copies
      Reprinted from Social Research
    - 17) "Stability in Late Capitalism" A Survey by Hans Neisser, 1954 Spring; 2 copies
    - 18) "Concept and Teaching of Economics" Comment by Hans Neisser, 1946 December
      Reprinted from American Economic Review. Vol. XXXVI, No.5
    - 19) "A Note on Pareto's I Theory of Production" by Hans Neisser, 1940 July; 3 copies
      Reprinted from Econometrica, Journal of the Ecometric Society. Vol. 8, No.3
    - 20) "Gross Capital Stock and Net Capital Stock: The Simplest Case" by Hans Neisser and E. Grosswald, 1960 February
      Reprinted from the Review of Economics and Statistics. Vol. XLII, No.1
    - 21) "Three Views of Method in Economics by H. Neisser, 1967 Summer; 3 copies
      Reprinted from Social Research. Vol. 34, No.2
    - 22) "The Phenomenological Approach in Social Science" by H. P. Neisser, 1959 December; 2 copies
      Reprinted from Philosophy and Phenomenological Research. Vol. XX, No.2
    - 23) "The United States Demand for Imports", 1953 May; 3 copies
      Reprinted from The American Economic Review. Vol. XLIII, No. 2
    - 24) "The External Equilibrium of the United States Economy" by Hans Neisser, 1964 Summer
      Reprinted from Social Research, Vol. 31, No. 2
    - 25) "Forum: Is the Public Debt a Burden on Future Generations" by Hans Neisser, 1961 Summer
    - 26) "Forum Economic Imperialism Again" by Sayre P. Schatz; Rejoinder by H. Neisser, Autumn 1961
    - 27) "The Concept of Technological Unemployment: A Reply to Mr. Hagen's Criticism" by Hans Neisser, 1942 September; 2 copies
      Reprinted from American Economic Review. Vol. XXXII, No. 3
    - 28) "The Problems of Reparations" by Hans Neisser (with the aid of the Committee on Economic Questions of the American Labor Conference in International Affairs, 1944 July
      Reprinted from the American Labor Conference of International Affairs)
    - 29) "The Aims of Federal Reserve Policy, 1951-1960" by Hans Neisser, Undated; 2 copies
      Reprinted from The Review of Economics and Statistics. Vol. XLII, No. 3, Part I, August 1960.
    - 30) Bleibt die Mark Stabil von Dr. Hans Neisser, Undated
    - 31) A supplementary note to the Article 7.: "The Static Theory of Aggregate Investment" by Hans Neisser, Undated; 4 copies
      Reprinted from Weltwirtschaftliches Archiv. Bd. XCVIII, 1967 I, pp. 1599
    - 32) Liquidtäat, von Dr. Hans Neisser, Kiel Bankwissenschaft. Heft 11 Berlin, 5. September 1932 Jahrang
    - 33) "Ankurbelung oder Inflation" by Hans Neisser, from Der Deutsche Volkswirt Zeitschrift Für Politik Und Wirtschaft, 6. Jahrg. Berlin NR. 3, Den 16. Oktober 1931
    - 34) "Der Kreislauf des Geldes von Privatdozent" Dr. Hans Neisser, Kiel, 1931 April
      Reprinted from: Weltwirtschastliches Archiv. 33. Band Heft 2
    - 35) "Der internationale Geldmarkt vor und nach dem Kriege". Bearbeiter Privatdozent Dr. Hans Neisser, 1929 April
      Reprinted by Weltwirtschastliches Archiv. 29. Band Heft 2
    - 36) "Kreislauftheretisches zur Gewinnsteuer von Hans Neisser", 1954
      Reprinted from: Finanzarchiv. Band 14 Heft 4
    - 37) Gustav Cassels. Theoretische Sozialokonomie - Von Dr. Hans Neisser - Breslau, Undated; 2 copies
    - 38) Arbeitszeit und Lohönhohe von Hans Neisser, 1935
      Reprinted from: Zeitschrift Für Nationalokonomie. Band VI, Heft 5
    - 39) "Equilibrium Dynamics, Behavior Dynamics, Stability Movement" by Hans Neisser, New York, Undated
      Reprinted by: Metroeconomica - International Review of Economics. Vol. XIII, April 1961. Fascicolo I.
    - 40) "Profit and Saving" by Hans Neisser, 1957
      Reprinted by: Separatum Kyklas (-) Fasc. 4
    - 41) "Economic, Logical and Mathematical Systems". Comment by Hans Neisser, 1959 Winter; 2 copies
      Reprinted from: Social Research
    - 42) "Ausfuhrprämien und Ausfuhrvergüdtungen" by Hans Neisser, Undated
      Reprinted from: unknown
    - 43) "Zur Rundfrage über "Substanzverluste" von Hans Neisser, 1932 August-1932 September
      Reprinted from: Archiv Für Sozilwissenschaft und Sozialpolitik. (2 copies) 67. Band, 6.Heft
    - 44) "Scarce Money" by Hans Neisser, 1957 Spring; 2 copies
    - 45) "Volksvermögen und Kassenbedarf von Hans Neisser", 1 Juli 1933
      Reprinted from: Archiv für Sozialwissenschaft und Sozialpolitik. 69. Band. 4. Heft
    - 46) "Geld - und Kapitalmarket. Privatversicherung" Dr. Hans Neisser, Keil, 1928 April
      Reprinted from: Weltwertschaftliches Archiv. 27. Band. Heft 2
    - 47) "General Overproduction - A Study of Say's Law of Markets" by Hans Neisser, 1934 August
      Reprinted from: The Journal of Political Economy. Vol. 42, No.4
    - 48) "Capital Gains and the Valuation of Capital and Income" by H. Neisser, 1941 July-1941 October; 2 copies
      Reprinted from: Econometrica, Journal of the Ecometric Society, Vol. 9, Nos.3&4.
    - 49) "Balanced Growth Under Constant Returns To Scale" Some Comments by Hans Neisser, 1954 October; 3 copies
      Reprinted from: Econometrica, Journal of the Econometric Society, Vol. 22, No. 4
    - 50) "Notenbankfreiheit- Von Privatdozent" Dr. Hans Neisser, Kiel, Oktober 1930
      Reprinted from: Weltwertschaftliches Arcliv 32. Band Heft 2
    - 51) "Das Gesetz vom abnehmenden Bodenertrag und die wirtschaftliche Entwicklung", von Hans Neisser, Undated
      Reprinted from: Archiv Für Sozialwissenschaft und Sozialpolitik. Separat - Abdruck aus Band. 49, Heft 2
    - 52) "Investment Criteria, Productivity, and Economic Development" Comment by Hans Neisser, 1956; 3 copies
      Reprinted from: The Quarterly Journal of Economics. Vol. LXX, November
    - 53) "Cyclical Fluctuations and Economic Growth" by Hans Neisser. Extract from:Oxford Economic Papers. New Series. - Vol. 13 No.2, 1961 June
    - 54) "Kreislauf Theoretisches zur Gewinnsteuer" von Hans Neisser, 1954; 3 copies
      Reprinted from: Finanzarchiv. Band 14, Heft 4
    - 55) "Ex Ante and Ex Past Propensity To Consume", by H. Neisser, 1959 October; 2 copies
      Reprinted from: The Oxford Economic Papers. New Series. Vol. 11, No. 8
    - 56) "Balanced Growth Under Constant Returns to Scale" Some Comments by Hans Neisser, 1954 October; 3 copies
      Reprinted from: Econometrica, Journal of the Econometric Society, Vol-22, No. 4
    - 57) "Die Liquidation der deutschen Währung". Von Dr. Hans Neisser. From:Der Oesterreichische Volkswirt 16. Jahr. No.41, Juli 1924
    - 58) "Government Net Contribution and Foreign Balance as Offset to Savings". By Hans Neisser, 1944 November; 2 copies
      Reprinted from: The Review of Economic Statistics. Vol. XXVI, No.4
    - 59) "Ueber "Goldrechenwährung" - Muszellen". Von Dr. Hans Neisser, Berlin Friedenau, 1923; Heft
      Reprinted from: Jahrbücher für Nationalökonomie und Statistik. Bd. 121
    - 60) "Das Neue Deutsche Steuersystem". Von Hans Neisser, Undated
      Reprinted from: Sonderdruck aus der Gesellschaft Jahrgang 1, Heft 3
    - 61) "Labor's Struggle for a Higher Standard of Living". By Hans Neisser, 1947 July; 2 copies
      Reprinted from: The American Journal of Economics and Sociology. Vol. 6 No.4.
    - 62) "The Nature of Import Propensities and The Foreign Trade Multiplier", by Hans Neisser, 1949 August
      Reprinted from: Economia Internazionale. Vol. II, No. 3
    - 63) "The United States Demand for Imports" by Hans P. Neisser, 1953 May; 2 copies
      Reprinted from: The American Economic Review - The Journal of The American Economic Association. Vol. XLIII, No.2
    - 64) "Lujo Brentano von Hans Neisser und Melchior Palyi, Undated
      Reprinted from: Bio-Bibliographische Beiträ age zur Geschichite Der Rechts - und Staatswissenschaften. Abteilung Staatswissenschaften: Heft 5
    - 65) "In Memorian: Gerhard Colm - 1887-1968". By Hans Neisser, 1969; 4 copies
      Reprinted from: Social Research. Vol-36, No. l, Spring
    - 66) "Discussion - Are Space and Time Real" by Hans Neisser, 1971 March; 2 copies
      Reprinted from: Philosophy & Phenomenological Research. Vol. XXXI, No.3
    - 67) "Economics" by Hans Neisser (1962), Undated
      Reprinted from: A New Survey of the Social Sciences
    - 68) The Static Theory of Aggregate Investment", by Hans Neisser, 1967
      Reprinted from: Weltwirtschaftliches Archiv. Band 98, Heft 1
    - 69) Der Geldmarkt unter dem Druck der Goldbewegungen". Von Privatdozent Dr. Hans Neisser, Kiel, Undated
      From: Magazen der Wirtschaft. 6 Jahrgang Berlin, 3. January 1930, Number 1.
  - Book Reviews, Undated; 2.2
    - 1)Deutschland und Frankreich, ihre Wirtschaft und Politik. 1923/24, herausgegeben von R. Kuczynski. Neue Folge, Berlin 1925. Verlag von R. L. Prager, 266 S. review by H. Neisser. from: Die Gesellschaft. Number 4 - 111. Jahrgang, 1926 April
    - 2) Carl Rodbertus -Jagetzow. Karlsruhe 1926. Verlag G, Braun. 398 S. review by H. Neisser. from: Die Gesellschaft. Number 6. IV Jahrgang, Juni 1927
    - 3) N. Georgescu-Rolgen:Analytical Economics, Cambridge, Mass. Harvard, 415 p., 1966
      Review by H. Neisser. From: The Journal of Philosophy. Vol. LXIV, No.7, April 13, 1967 (5 copies).
    - 4)Economics and the Public Interest by R. T, Gill. Pacific Palisades, Calif.: Goodyear Publishing Co. pp. 306, 1968; 2 copies
    - 4)The Economic Problem, by R. L. Heilbroner. Englewood Cliffs, N.J.: Prentice-Hall, 1968, pp.XX, 652, Review by H. Neisser, Undated
    - 5)Der Lagerzyklus - Lagerbewegung und Konjunkturverlauf in empirischer Sicht by Harry Schimmler. Berlin: Dunker & Humbolt, pp.113. Dm 12, 1958; 2 copies
      Review by Hans Neisser.
    - 6) Halasi, Adalbert:Die Goldwährung (unter Mitwirkung von N. Leites). Berlin, Carl Heymanns Verlag, 1933. VIII und 145 Seiten, Undated
      Review by H. Neisser, from: Literatur Anzeiger.